<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tim&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://timothytfchan.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tim&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://timothytfchan.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common-sense sentience is dubious</title>
      <link>https://timothytfchan.github.io/posts/common-sense-sentience-is-dubious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothytfchan.github.io/posts/common-sense-sentience-is-dubious/</guid>
      <description>Summary This post lays out some problems/uncertainties I have with various stances in the philosophy of mind, almost all of which implicitly or explicitly privilege &amp;lsquo;common sense&amp;rsquo;. The main point is that our intuitions aren&amp;rsquo;t shaped to be useful at finding out whether something actually experiences/experiences things in a particular way. Instead, those intuitions are strongly influenced by (1) the evolutionary need to navigate ancestral social environments and (2) what your culture believes - which I argue don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have much to do with the truth of the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking of Humans as &#34;Concept Classifiers&#34;</title>
      <link>https://timothytfchan.github.io/posts/thinking-of-humans-as-concept-classifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothytfchan.github.io/posts/thinking-of-humans-as-concept-classifiers/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This post concerns epistemology rather than ontology. Claims are not about what “seemingly physics-independent” phenomena exist, and how they are, but rather concern how we form ideas about such things.
Summary Our brains, as physical objects, physically create and utilize various concepts - including seemingly “physics-independent” concepts such as morality, selfhood, and the sentience of others. Their physical origins cast doubt on whether these physically-formed, &amp;ldquo;seemingly physics-independent&amp;rdquo; concepts truly reflect corresponding supposedly “non-physical” realities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
